{
    "id": "573359a679a3482bb4c43aa13dcd398d",
    "title": "Sentence Completion Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If I hadn’t dropped out of college I …………………… a better job.",
            "description": "In the third conditional we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "can find",
                "could find",
                "could have found"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He took ……………………. his coat.",
            "description": "To take off a coat is to remove it.",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "out",
                "off"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "You can do with me what you ……………………",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "want",
                "wanted",
                "are wanting"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I know you ……………………. lying.",
            "description": "Either could be used here. When the main verb is the present tense, the subordinate verb can be in any tense depending upon the context.",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "were",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………. we tried, we could not find a solution to the problem.",
            "description": "Fronted adjectives/adverbs are possible in a structure with as or though.",
            "answers": [
                "Hard though",
                "Hard as",
                "Though hard"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The lecture was ………………………..",
            "description": "The present participle denotes the people or things that make us feel in a certain way. The past participle denotes how the people or things are feeling.",
            "answers": [
                "boring",
                "bored"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Never ………………………. seen such a mess.",
            "description": "Inversion is used when a sentence starts with only or hardly or seldom.",
            "answers": [
                "I have",
                "have I"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Hardly …………………… we arrived when the trouble started.",
            "description": "Had is used before the past participle form of the verb. ",
            "answers": [
                "did",
                "had"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "‘I have quit smoking.’ ‘……………….. have I.’",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "So",
                "Either",
                "Neither"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "As soon as she received the message, she …………………….. for home.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "had left",
                "has left"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "They ……………………….. many objections.",
            "description": "Raise is transitive. Rise is intransitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "raised",
                "rose",
                "risen"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If I knew the answer, I ……………………. you.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "would tell",
                "will tell",
                "would have told"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}